Guide to the Siegfried Sassoon Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Siegfried Sassoon papers
1914-1967
GEN MSS 768
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.46
(4 boxes)
Sassoon, Siegfried, 1886-1967
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William S. Reese (Yale 1977), 2007 and 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Sassoon, Siegfried (1886-1967)
Siegfried Sassoon (1886-1967) was an English poet, writer, and soldier. A decorated veteran of World War I, he was one of the leading poets of the war and an outspoken anti-war advocate. Sassoon later worked as a literary editor and novelist.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: November 2007 Acquisition; and January 2015 Acquisition.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, photographs, a scrapbook, and other papers by or related to Siegfried Sassoon. Spanning from the beginning of the first World War to Sassoon's death in 1967, the papers document his writings, including the novel Sherston's Progress, the poetry collections Satirical Poems and The Heart's Journey, and other works.
Authors, English -- 20th Century; English poetry -- 20th Century; Poets, English -- 20th Century; Soldiers -- Great Britain; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918 -- Literature and the war; World War, 1914-1918 -- Personal narrative, English; Photographs; Authors -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Poets -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Soldiers -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Sassoon, Siegfried, 1886-1967
- November 2007 Acquisition, 1914-1967; 1.46; (4 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1914-1957 (Box 1)
  - De le Mare, Richard, 1938 January 21 (Box 1)
  - Graves, Charles, 1917 March 26 (Box 1)
  - Graves, Robert, 1925 April 29 (Box 1)
  - McCallum, Neil - Journey with a Pistol - proof with correspondence, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Palmer, Hebert (Box 1)
  - Palmer, Hebert, 1937 February 1 (Box 1)
  - The Royal Welch Fusiliers, Presentation of Colours to the 1st, 2nd & 4th Battalions by Her Majesty The Queen, 1954 July 23 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1916-1918 (Box 1)
  - War Resisters' International, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - To Victory, 1916 January 1 (Box 1)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried to William Heinemann, [1917] August 10 (Box 1)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Notes, circa 1919 (Box 1)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - 3 ALS to Sacheverell and Georgia Sitwell - 2 photographs, 1923-1932 (Box 1)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Satirical Poems, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Heart's Journey, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - To My Mother, 1928; 2 (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - 10 postcards to Stephen Tennant, 1931-1937 (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Sherston's Progress - 1936, 2 (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Questionnaire, 1937 April 1 (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Collected Poems - proof, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Sport and Literature, 1950s (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - The Tasking, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried to Desmond Flower, 1967 May 16 (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried to Desmond Flower, 1967 May 26 (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Omar - variants, undated (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Photograph, undated (Box 2)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried - Complete Memoirs of George Sherston, proof copy, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Materials removed from books, 1930s-1950s; 38 (Box 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Also contains loose correspondence.
- January 2015 Acquisition, 1928, 1942; 2 folders
  - J. C. Dunn autograph letter signed to Siegfried Sassoon, 1928 December 13 (Box 4)
  - John W. Davies autograph letter signed to Siegfried Sassoon, 1942 June 24 (Box 4)